Etki Acilan

etki@metu.edu.tr | etkiacilan.github.io

OBJECTIVE

Graduate student looking for opportunities.

SUMMARY

I am a master's student studying under the supervision of Dr. Murat Gol at Middle East Technical University with a major in Electrical Engineering. I am also a Research and Teaching Assistant at the same department. My main research area is Power System State & Parameter Estimation. I have experience in Kalman Filters, other estimators and optimization methods on MATLAB and Python. I have been the teaching assistant for Power System Analysis courses. I have worked on industrial projects where I implemented well-known state estimation tools.

RESEARCH INTERESTS

Power System Static State Estimation, Power System Dynamic State Estimation, Parameter Estimation

EDUCATION

Middle East Technical University

Ankara, Turkey

MSc. Electrical and Electronics Engineering, Power Systems

September 2019 – Present

Supervisor: Dr. Murat Gol

Middle East Technical University

Ankara, Turkey

BSc. Electrical and Electronics Engineering, Power Systems GPA: 3.35/4 September 2015 – June 2019

GPA: 3.86/4

WORK EXPERIENCE

Middle East Technical University

Ankara, Turkey

Teaching Assistant, Department of Electrical and Electronics Engineering

February 2020 – Present

- Power System Analysis I & II
- High Voltage Techniques I & II
- Electrical Equipment and Applications

Middle East Technical University

Ankara, Turkey June 2019 — Present

Research Assistant, Power System Analysis Laboratory

• Participated in projects mentioned in Projects section.

Ulusoy Electric Ankara, Turkey

Intern, Production and Quality Control

September 2018 – October 2018

• Observed the production line of MV equipment.

AF-Mercados EMI Ankara, Turkey

Intern. Distribution Network Planning

June 2018 – September 2018

- Worked at Master Plan of First DISCO.
- Modeled distribution networks of four cities on DigSilent Power Factory

PROJECTS

Implementation of Power Systems SE Algorithms ASELSAN

January 2020 - April 2021 (Expected)

- Implemented traditional WLS-SE, Transformer Tap Estimator, Observability Analysis, and Bad Data Analysis tools on MATLAB considering sparse nature of the matrices.
- Implemented a Very Short-Term Load Forecast Aided WLS Hybrid-SE.
- \bullet Wrote technical reports of Topology Processor and Hybrid-SE.

Power Plant Parameter Calibration Tool

October 2020 - Present

- Implemented Ensemble Kalman Filter based Power Plant Parameter Calibration Algorithm using PSS/E API and analytical models on Python.
- Presented algorithms on technical meetings.

ALGORITHMS

• Weighted Least Squares, Kalman Filter, Extended Kalman Filter, Unscented Kalman Filter, Ensemble Kalman Filter, Newton-Raphson Method, Depth-First Search, and other common optimization algorithms such as line search methods.

SKILLS

Programming Language: Python, MATLAB

Simulation and Analysis Software: PSS/E (including psspy), DigSilent PowerFactory

COURSES

- Power System Stability and Dynamics
- Power System Real-Time Monitoring and Control
- System Identification
- Optimization
- Power System Analysis I & II
- Distribution Systems
- Electrical Power Quality Monitoring and Improvement
- Nonlinear Control Systems
- Feedback Systems
- Economic Operation of Power System
- Linear Systems Theory

HONORS

National Academic Personnel and Postgraduate Education Entrance Exam (GRE Equivalent Exam in Turkey)

Ranked 313rd among 119000 participants

Dean's Honor Roll Achieved High Honor Roll 5 times in 8 terms

National University Entrance Exam Ranked 1665th among 2 million participants

LANGUAGES

English Professional working proficiency

Turkish Native